### Thaer Shakhshir

Orléans, ON

(709) 330-2846 • thaer.shakhshir@mun.ca • linkedin.com/in/tshakhshir

# IT Technical Support

## **Summary**

Knowledgeable IT support technician with 4 - 5 years of experience assisting customers with Hardware and Software related issues. Provided rigorous 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> Tiers technical Support to clients. Enlightened in networking principles, protocols and applications. Known for exceptional written and oral communication, time management, teamwork, and multitasking skills. Earned a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, in addition to various professional certificates.

## **Highlights**

• Linux Terminal

Proficient troubleshooter
PuTTy

SQL DB Management

Linux Desktop

• CompTIA A+

FileZilla

• HTML

• Windows 10

Ticketing Systems

• Jira

Python

Virtualization

hMailServer

QA Software testing
Microsoft Office Suite 365

# Work Experience

### **Junior Support Engineer**

2019 - 2020

Unlimi-Tech Software Inc - Ottawa, Canada

- Provided 1st and 2nd tier support to clients via Support tickets and live chat
- Provided technical solutions, fixes, updates and workarounds on Support Tickets
- Replicated customer issues in a test environment and verify resolutions prior to providing software fixes
- Identified and troubleshot software and environmental issues and eliminated instabilities

### Customer Service Representative (Call Center)

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

MSi Corp- Ottawa, Canada

- Coordinated a variety of orders for new installations, moves, adds, changes, and customer win-backs
- Determined and negotiated the best solution, and chose the most appropriate procedure to follow
- Closed sales and efficiently placed orders within allotted time frames
- Adhered to call duration and scheduling requirements

#### **User Support Technician**

2012 - 2017

Memorial University - St. John's, Canada

- Managed different databases for various technical and IT needs
- Resolved technical issues relating to accounts and network printing purposes
- Provided instructions on how to use university accounts for new on-boarding students
- Tested and reported network issues to management and technical teams
- Tools: Desire to Learn (D2L)'s administrative web tools and databases

Education	
<b>Bachelor of Science in Computer Science</b> Memorial University of Newfoundland - St. John's, Canada	2012 - 2018
Professional Development	
Master the Linux Command Line (Udemy)	2020
The Complete Web Developer online course (Udemy)	2019
Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)	2009
Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA)	2009
Volunteer Experience	
Software Developer - Ready for STEM St. John's, Canada	Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019
Event Organizer - Young Adult Cancer Canada(YACC) St. John's, Canada	2018 - 2019
Exam Invigilator - International English Language Testing System St. John's, Canada	Nov. 2018